A Guide to the Fairfax Ferns Garden Club Records, 1957-2018
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Fairfax Ferns Garden Club Records, 1957-2018
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 05-69
2.5 linear feet
The Fairfax Ferns Garden Club Records consists of 2.5 linear feet and spans the years 1957-2018 and consist of minutes, newsletters, yearbooks, awards and certificates, photographs, newspaper articles, and other ephemera. Subjects covered are the history and activities of the Fairfax Ferns.
Fairfax Ferns Garden Club
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Donated by Hildie Carne on December 31, 2018
Historical and Biographical Information
The Greenway Hills Garden Club was formed in 1957 in the new Greenway Hills subdivision, now known as Old Lee Hills. In March 1960, the club’s name changed to Fairfax Ferns as many new residents moved into the neighborhood. The group became affiliated with National Garden Clubs, Inc. in 1963.
The Fairfax Ferns’ mission is to promote an interest in gardening and to encourage civic improvements. The club is very involved in the City of Fairfax’s gardening needs which included designing, planting, and maintaining the Kitty Pozer Garden in Old Town Fairfax. The Fairfax Ferns host flower shows every other year which are open free to the public.
The club publishes a monthly newsletter called the “Fern Fax” and an annual yearbook which is dedicated to an outstanding member or a notable person in the City of Fairfax. Monthly meetings are held the first Monday of the month at the City of Fairfax Regional Library. A program is presented at the meeting relating to a particular gardening issue. The club also has other meetings such as tours, workshops, and demonstrations.
Scope and Content
The Fairfax Ferns Garden Club Records consists of 2.5 linear feet and spans the years 1957-2018 and consist of minutes, newsletters, yearbooks, awards and certificates, photographs, newspaper articles, and other ephemera. Awards include certificates of achievement, appreciation, congratulations, exhibition, and recognition. The Awards and Projects notebook contains photos of the Northern Virginia Mental Health Institute; Fairfax Nursing Home; Commonwealth Doctors Hospital; Fairfax High School; and Earp’s Ordinary. Subjects covered are the history and activities of the Fairfax Ferns.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Fairfax (Va.) - History; Fairfax Ferns Garden Club; Gardening - Societies, etc. - Virginia - Fairfax; Greenway Hills Garden Club
Container List
- Greenway Hills Garden Club Minutes, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Fairfax Ferns Garden Club Minutes, 1960-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Fairfax Ferns Garden Club Minutes, 1972-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Newspaper clippings, 1971-2018 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Programs, Volunteer of the Year, 1995-2012 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Flower Show Schedules, 1964-2018 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Awards, 1974-2016 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Notebook, Awards and Projects [contains photographs], 1969-2018 (Box 2)
- Yearbooks, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Yearbooks, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Yearbooks, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Yearbooks, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Yearbooks, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Yearbooks, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Yearbooks, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Yearbooks, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Yearbooks, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Yearbooks, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Yearbooks, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Yearbooks, 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Yearbooks, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Yearbooks, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Yearbooks, 2001-2003 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Yearbooks, 2003-2005 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Yearbooks, 2005-2007 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Yearbooks, 2007-2009 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Yearbooks, 2009-2013 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Yearbooks, 2013-2017 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Newsletters, 1962-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Newsletters, 1970-1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Newsletters, 1980-1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Newsletters, 1991-1999 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Newsletters, 2000-2005 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Newsletters, 2006-2018 (Box 5, Folder 6)